themerkle.com 2019-11-22

# Privacy Policy » The Merkle Hash

#### **Privacy Policy for  themerkle.com**

Please read the below privacy policy, by using this website you agree to our privacy policy outlined below:

The privacy of our visitors is important to us.

At themerkle.com, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit themerkle.com, and how we safeguard your information.

themerkle.com may collect personal information about the users using cookies. themerkle.com will use that information to monitor site usage, keep track of advertisements, or the purpose stated on the form (such as subscribing to our email newsletter).

themerkle.com will protect the personal information with reasonable safeguards against theft or loss. Your personal information will not be shared with or published to any third party without your consent. To remove yourself from the mailing list, click unsubscribe on any of the emails. We do not retain personal information for any purposes other than stated.

themerkle.com does not endorse any third party vendors advertising on this platform. You may disable cookies in your browser if you want to opt out.  Alternatively, you can opt out of some third-party vendor’s use of cookies for interest-based advertising by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

#### **How we collect information**

We may collect personally identifiable information if you voluntarily provide it to us. We may also obtain your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider), the session ID of your browser, length of time you spent on our website, and other non personally identifiable information as you interact with our services.

#### **What we use your information for**

We will only use your personal information that was voluntarily provided to us to send you newsletters. In the case of a rebrand or change of domain, we reserve the right to transfer the information to the new brand and domain.

We use non personally identifiable information to serve you better tailored ads, to calculate the amount of visitors we get (using Google Analytics), to serve you customized pages, and to deliver tailored content for you (such as news and reviews).

We may also use your voluntarily provided information to allow you to comment on articles on our website.

We have the right to disclose your contact info to a third party that claims that content you posted violated copyright. You further agree that we may share non-personally identifiable information with third parties.

#### **Log Files**

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

We may also collect your name and email if you provide it to use for our newsletter. By voluntarily providing us this information, you agree to our use of your information according to this privacy policy.

We may collect information about legal entities that visit our website, we may collect their name, address, website link, and other similar identifying information.

#### **Cookies and Web Beacons**

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as posting comments.

We also use third party advertisements on themerkle.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

###### **DoubleClick DART Cookies**

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”).

The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.

You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting [http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx](https://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx)

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

#### **Data Retention**

We will retain your data as long as necessary in order to provide you services, or as required by law. We will retain this information to settle disputes and fulfill our legal obligations.

It is your right to have access to any information we stored about you. You can contact us as **contact@themerkle.com** at any time to inquire whether we have any of your personal or non-personal information.

#### **How we protect your information**

We employ a few different technical and administrative safeguards to do our best to keep your information secure. We use Cloudflare as a reverse proxy to mitigate any malicious access to our servers. We use a firewall to filter traffic, and a secure database to keep our data against unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

Unfortunately no data transmission method is 100% secure these days, and this privacy policy does not constitute warranty in regards to keeping your personal information secure. You agree to transmit personal information to us at your own risk.

#### **Privacy Concerns**

You have the right to object to our use of your information. You may opt out of any emails by clicking the unsubscribe button. You may also opt our of any push notifications by either going into your browser settings or clicking the gear icon on any notification.

We take privacy concerns seriously and if you believe that we haven’t complied with our privacy policy please contact us at **contact@themerkle.com**.

#### **Right to be Forgotten**

It is your right to have your personal information removed from our servers. If you would no longer like us to provide you services and would no longer like us to process your personal information please write to us at **contact@themerkle.com**.

This policy is subject to change without notice, it was last updated on July 14th, 2018.
